Juulia Suvilehto

DATA SCIENTIST, RESEARCHER

CONTACT



juulia.suvilehto@iki.fi



0700895005



https://github.com/jtsuvile www.linkedin.com/ in/suvilehto/

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING
LANGUAGES
R (incl. tidyverse,
RMarkdown)
Python (incl. NumPy
Pandas, Nilearn, Scikitlearn, matplotlib)

Matlab (incl. SPM, Statistics & Machine learning toolbox)

OTHER TOOLS Git Subversion Slurm html, CSS, php SQL

NATURAL LANGUAGES
Finnish native
English fluent
Swedish very
good

PROFILE

Data scientist with background in neuroscience. I have extensive experience in cleaning, analysing and visualising large data sets. I excel at explaining complex technical concepts in ways that are approachable to non-specialists, such as medical professionals.

WORK EXPERIENCE

2019-> **POSTDOCTORAL RESEARCH FELLOW,** LINKÖPING UNIVERSITY, LINKÖPING, SWEDEN

- Running and supporting multiple projects investigating individual differences in responses to socio-affective stimuli.
- Building data processing pipelines and carrying out exploratory data analyses using Python and R.
- Driving initiatives to re-use existing data and supporting colleagues in moving to reproducible data analysis practices.
- Created and taught a popular course "R for scientific data analysis".

2018- 2019 **POSTDOCTORAL RESEARCHER,** UNIVERSITY OF OXFORD, OXFORD, THE UK

- Designed and wrote ethics application for a study to assess deidentification algorithm used on health records in research (UK-CRIS).
- Worked as a part of a larger team investigating the utility of existing data on detecting and treating mood disorders and improving FAIRness of the existing data.
- Tracked down existing data sets and evaluated their usefulness for the project.
- Trained colleagues in using version control (git).

2014- 2018 **PHD CANDIDATE,** AALTO UNIVERSITY, HELSINKI, FINLAND 2013-2014 **RESEARCH ASSISTANT,** AALTO UNIVERSITY, HELSINKI, FINLAND

- Conducted research on human social and affective systems which have resulted in 5 peer-reviewed journal articles.
- Developed data collection systems with php, html and CSS; built data analysis pipelines using Matlab, Python and R.
- Analysed imaging and questionnaire data using machine learning.
- Managed projects with collaborators from multiple countries and different professional backgrounds.

Juulia Suvilehto

DATA SCIENTIST, RESEARCHER

2013 **ASSOCIATE PRODUCT MANAGER,** CRF HEALTH (NOW SIGNANT HEALTH) HELSINKI, FINLAND

- Master's thesis position (exjobb) in the Health Outcomes division.
- Helped launch a new initiative by investigating the suitability of using subjects' own devices in clinical trials from regulatory and practical perspectives.

2011-2012 JUNIOR BIOINFORMATICIAN, EUFORMATICS OY, ESPOO, FINLAND

- First employee while the company was still a start-up.
- Designed and implemented parts of the data analysis and data management software.
- Created training materials, carried out technical training and acted as technical support for the non-technical end-users.
- Worked with SQL and Oracle Apex. Version control in subversion.

EDUCATION

2018 DOCTOR OF SCIENCE (TECHNOLOGY) Aalto University, Finland

Systems Neuroscience, pass with distinction

2014 MASTER OF SCIENCE (TECHNOLOGY) Aalto University, Finland

Computational and Cognitive Biosciences, pass with distinction

2013 BACHELOR OF SCIENCE (TECHNOLOGY) Aalto University, Finland

Computational and Cognitive Biosciences, incl. exchange year in Linköping University

RELEVANT TRAINING

DATA SCIENCE INITIATIVE OF ÉCOLE POLYTECHNIQUE AND DATAIA INSTITUTE, FRANCE

Data Science Summer School (2019)

AALTO UNIVERSITY, FINLAND

Some of the relevant courses which were completed as a part of the Bachelor's and Master's degrees in Science (Technology)

Data Structures and Algorithms,

Machine Learning: Basic Principles,

Designing Services,

Exercise on User-Centered Product Development,

Special Assignment on User-Centered Product Development